<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.malinga.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://www.malinga.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-03T23:03:26+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Romesh Malinga Perera</title><subtitle>Human | Engineer | Researcher </subtitle><entry><title type="html">HMAB: Teaching Databases to Tune Themselves</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/hmab-self-driving-database-tuning-explained/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HMAB: Teaching Databases to Tune Themselves"/><published>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/hmab-self-driving-database-tuning-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/hmab-self-driving-database-tuning-explained/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/DBA-Bandit-Self-driving-index-tuning-under-ad-hoc-analytical-workloads-with-safety-guarantees-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/DBA-Bandit-Self-driving-index-tuning-under-ad-hoc-analytical-workloads-with-safety-guarantees-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/DBA-Bandit-Self-driving-index-tuning-under-ad-hoc-analytical-workloads-with-safety-guarantees-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/DBA-Bandit-Self-driving-index-tuning-under-ad-hoc-analytical-workloads-with-safety-guarantees.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>If you’ve ever worked with databases, you know they can be finicky. The same database can run a query in seconds or hours depending on how it’s set up. Traditionally, this optimization has been the job of specialized database administrators (DBAs) who spend countless hours tweaking settings and creating “indexes” and “materialized views”—special structures that help databases find data faster.</p> <p>But what if the database could learn to optimize itself?</p> <h2 id="the-problem-database-tuning-is-hard">The Problem: Database Tuning is Hard</h2> <p>Imagine you’re organizing a massive library. You could arrange books alphabetically by title, by author, or by subject. Each arrangement makes some searches faster and others slower. Now imagine the library has millions of books, and people are constantly asking for different combinations of books. How do you organize it?</p> <p>This is essentially what happens in databases. <strong>Indexes</strong> are like card catalogs that help you find specific information quickly. <strong>Materialized views</strong> are like pre-organized reading lists for common requests. Creating the right combination of these structures is crucial for performance, but it’s incredibly complex:</p> <ul> <li>There are often millions of possible configurations</li> <li>Traditional tools rely on the database’s “cost estimator,” which is frequently wrong</li> <li>Workloads change over time—what worked yesterday might not work today</li> <li>Creating these structures takes time and resources</li> </ul> <h2 id="enter-hmab-a-smarter-approach">Enter HMAB: A Smarter Approach</h2> <p>HMAB (Hierarchical Multi-Armed Bandits) takes a fundamentally different approach. Instead of relying on estimates, it <strong>learns from experience</strong>.</p> <h3 id="the-multi-armed-bandit-analogy">The Multi-Armed Bandit Analogy</h3> <p>The name comes from a classic problem in machine learning: imagine you’re in a casino with multiple slot machines (one-armed bandits). Each machine has a different, unknown payout rate. How do you figure out which machines are best while maximizing your winnings?</p> <p>You face a dilemma:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Explore</strong>: Try different machines to learn which are best</li> <li><strong>Exploit</strong>: Keep playing the machines that have worked well so far</li> </ul> <p>HMAB applies this same principle to database tuning. It strategically explores different configurations (indexes and views) while exploiting what it has learned to keep performance high.</p> <h3 id="how-hmab-works">How HMAB Works</h3> <p>HMAB uses a clever two-layer hierarchy:</p> <p><strong>Layer 1: Specialists</strong></p> <ul> <li>Multiple specialized “bandits” each focus on a specific area</li> <li>One set handles materialized views for the entire database</li> <li>Another set handles indexes, with one specialist per table</li> <li>Each specialist recommends candidate structures</li> </ul> <p><strong>Layer 2: The Coordinator</strong></p> <ul> <li>Takes all the candidates from Layer 1</li> <li>Decides which combination to actually use</li> <li>Learns which structures work well together</li> </ul> <p>This hierarchy is powerful because:</p> <ol> <li><strong>It’s modular</strong>: You can add or remove specialists without disrupting the system</li> <li><strong>It’s efficient</strong>: Specialists can run in parallel on multi-core systems</li> <li><strong>It learns from reality</strong>: Instead of trusting the database’s estimates, HMAB creates structures and observes actual performance</li> </ol> <h3 id="a-smart-optimization-hypothetical-checks">A Smart Optimization: Hypothetical Checks</h3> <p>Creating database structures is expensive. HMAB reduces this cost with a clever trick: before actually creating a structure, it asks the database optimizer, “Would you even use this?” If the answer is no, HMAB skips creation entirely, saving up to 58% of creation time.</p> <p>This hybrid approach gets the best of both worlds: learning from real execution while avoiding unnecessary work.</p> <h2 id="the-results-impressive-gains">The Results: Impressive Gains</h2> <p>We tested HMAB against state-of-the-art commercial database tuning tools using industry-standard benchmarks (TPC-H, TPC-DS, and real-world datasets like IMDb). The results were striking:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Up to 96% performance improvement</strong> over commercial tools on complex workloads</li> <li><strong>91% gain</strong> on modern analytical benchmarks (TPC-DS)</li> <li><strong>Strong performance on dynamic workloads</strong> where queries constantly change—a scenario where traditional tools struggle</li> </ul> <p>Even on uniform datasets where traditional tools excel, HMAB remains competitive while offering far better performance on the skewed, messy data that real-world systems actually encounter.</p> <h3 id="why-traditional-tools-struggle">Why Traditional Tools Struggle</h3> <p>Traditional tools have two main problems:</p> <ol> <li><strong>They rely on estimates</strong>: Database optimizers estimate query costs, but these estimates can be wildly wrong, especially with complex queries or skewed data</li> <li><strong>They need representative workloads</strong>: You have to tell them what queries to optimize for—but in dynamic systems, workloads constantly change</li> </ol> <p>HMAB sidesteps both issues by continuously learning from actual execution.</p> <h2 id="what-this-means-for-the-future">What This Means for the Future</h2> <p>HMAB represents a shift toward <strong>self-driving databases</strong>. Instead of requiring expert DBAs to constantly monitor and tune systems, databases can learn to optimize themselves.</p> <p>This is particularly important as:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Cloud databases</strong> serve unpredictable, multi-tenant workloads</li> <li><strong>Data becomes more skewed and complex</strong>, breaking traditional optimizer assumptions</li> <li><strong>Real-time analytics</strong> demand constant adaptation to changing query patterns</li> </ul> <p>The system even comes with <strong>provable performance guarantees</strong>—something rare in machine learning approaches—ensuring it won’t make things catastrophically worse while learning.</p> <h2 id="the-technical-innovation">The Technical Innovation</h2> <p>For those interested in the technical details, HMAB introduces several innovations:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Hierarchical Multi-Armed Bandits</strong>: A novel bandit architecture that extends contextual and combinatorial bandits into a hierarchy, enabling efficient handling of massive action spaces while leveraging parallel processing</li> <li><strong>Context design</strong>: Each specialist uses a compact representation of database features, allowing efficient learning</li> <li><strong>Reward structure</strong>: The system learns from both execution time improvements and creation costs</li> <li><strong>Hierarchical architecture</strong>: The first system to holistically tune multiple types of physical design structures (indexes AND views) using machine learning</li> </ul> <h2 id="try-it-yourself">Try It Yourself</h2> <p>The code is available as an artifact for the research community. Whether you’re a database administrator curious about automated tuning, a researcher working on database optimization, or a developer dealing with slow queries, HMAB demonstrates that databases can indeed learn to tune themselves.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Read the full paper</strong>: <a href="https://www.vldb.org/pvldb/vol16/p216-perera.pdf">HMAB: Self-Driving Hierarchy of Bandits for Integrated Physical Database Design Tuning</a> published in PVLDB 2022.</p> <p><strong>Authors</strong>: R. Malinga Perera, Bastian Oetomo, Benjamin I. P. Rubinstein, and Renata Borovica-Gajic from the University of Melbourne.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="research"/><category term="databases"/><category term="machine-learning"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A simple explanation of how HMAB uses machine learning to automatically optimize database performance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TPC-H HTAP: INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE Queries for Skewed Datasets</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/tpc-h-htap-workload-skewed-datasets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TPC-H HTAP: INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE Queries for Skewed Datasets"/><published>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/tpc-h-htap-workload-skewed-datasets</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/tpc-h-htap-workload-skewed-datasets/"><![CDATA[<p>While HTAP (Hybrid Transactional/Analytical Processing) workloads exist for database benchmarking, <strong>none of them support highly skewed data distributions</strong> like those found in real-world systems. This is a significant gap because production databases rarely have uniformly distributed data.</p> <h2 id="the-missing-piece">The Missing Piece</h2> <p><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=52430">TPC-H Skew</a> provides realistic, skewed data distributions that mirror production environments where some customers place thousands of orders while others place just one, and some products are bestsellers while others barely sell. However, TPC-H Skew only provides analytical (SELECT) queries.</p> <p>Modern databases need to handle both:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Analytical queries</strong>: Complex reports and aggregations (OLAP)</li> <li><strong>Transactional queries</strong>: INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE operations (OLTP)</li> </ul> <p>To test databases under realistic mixed workloads, we need both—with skewed data.</p> <h2 id="the-solution">The Solution</h2> <p>The <a href="https://github.com/malingaperera/TPC_H_HTAP">TPC-H HTAP project</a> generates INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE queries for TPC-H Skew (and standard TPC-H). This enables realistic HTAP benchmarking where:</p> <ul> <li>Analytical queries run on skewed data</li> <li>Transactional queries continuously modify the database</li> <li>The workload reflects what actually happens in production</li> </ul> <h2 id="how-to-use-it">How to Use It</h2> <ol> <li>Set up <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=52430">TPC-H Skew</a> and generate your base dataset</li> <li>Generate seeds: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">./Debug/dbgen -v -O s -s 10</code></li> <li>Generate refresh data: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">./Debug/dbgen -v -U 2 -s 10</code></li> <li>Copy generated files to the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tpc_h_data</code> folder</li> <li>Customize SQL syntax in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">tpc_h_htap_qgen.py</code> for your database</li> <li>Run the script to generate INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE queries</li> </ol> <p>The tool is database-agnostic (SQL Server syntax provided) and allows you to configure which records to update based on your testing needs.</p> <h2 id="why-this-matters">Why This Matters</h2> <p>This benchmark was crucial for evaluating <a href="https://malingaperera.github.io/blog/2026/hmab-self-driving-database-tuning-explained/">HMAB</a>, our self-driving database tuning system. HTAP workloads with skewed data are particularly challenging because:</p> <ul> <li>The database structure changes as inserts and deletes occur</li> <li>Indexes that speed up transactions might slow down analytics</li> <li>Data skew makes optimizer estimates unreliable</li> </ul> <p>Testing on realistic workloads revealed that HMAB achieves up to 96% performance improvement precisely because it learns from actual execution rather than relying on estimates.</p> <p>Without realistic HTAP benchmarks with skewed data, we optimize for idealized scenarios that don’t reflect production reality</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Code</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/malingaperera/TPC_H_HTAP">TPC-H HTAP Workload on GitHub</a><br/> <strong>TPC-H Skew</strong>: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=52430">Download from Microsoft</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="databases"/><category term="benchmarking"/><category term="HTAP"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generating transactional queries for TPC-H Skew to enable realistic HTAP workload testing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Complete Interval Timer - Privacy Policy</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/complete-interval-timer-privacy-policy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete Interval Timer - Privacy Policy"/><published>2025-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/complete-interval-timer-privacy-policy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/complete-interval-timer-privacy-policy/"><![CDATA[<p>Last updated: December 30, 2025</p> <h2 id="overview">Overview</h2> <p>Complete Interval Timer (“the App”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy explains how we handle your information.</p> <h2 id="data-collection">Data Collection</h2> <p>The App stores the following data <strong>locally on your device only</strong>:</p> <ul> <li>Workout presets (names, timings, segment configurations)</li> <li>App settings and preferences</li> </ul> <p><strong>We do NOT collect</strong>:</p> <ul> <li>Personal information</li> <li>Location data</li> <li>Usage analytics</li> <li>Any information that leaves your device</li> </ul> <h2 id="data-storage">Data Storage</h2> <ul> <li>All data is stored locally using Android’s SharedPreferences</li> <li>No data is transmitted to external servers</li> <li>No accounts or authentication required</li> </ul> <h2 id="data-sharing">Data Sharing</h2> <p>We do not share any data with third parties. Period.</p> <h2 id="importexport">Import/Export</h2> <p>Users can export presets to JSON files for backup or sharing. These files remain under your control.</p> <h2 id="permissions">Permissions</h2> <p>The app uses the following permissions:</p> <ul> <li>Storage access (READ/WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE): Only for importing and exporting preset files</li> </ul> <h2 id="third-party-services">Third-Party Services</h2> <p>The App uses the following Android system services:</p> <ul> <li>Text-to-Speech (TTS): For voice announcements during workouts</li> <li>Wakelock: To prevent screen from dimming during active workouts</li> </ul> <p>No data is sent to third parties.</p> <h2 id="data-deletion">Data Deletion</h2> <p>You can delete all your data by:</p> <ol> <li>Deleting presets individually in the app</li> <li>Clearing app data in Android Settings</li> <li>Uninstalling the app</li> </ol> <h2 id="childrens-privacy">Children’s Privacy</h2> <p>The App does not collect any information from users. It is suitable for all ages.</p> <h2 id="changes-to-this-policy">Changes to This Policy</h2> <p>We will notify users of any material changes by updating this page.</p> <h2 id="contact">Contact</h2> <p>For questions about this privacy policy, contact: reachdsh@gmail.com</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="legal"/><category term="privacy"/><category term="android"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy Policy for Complete Interval Timer Android Application]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Updated 2022 Nov - Water Bill Calculator – Sri Lanka</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updated 2022 Nov - Water Bill Calculator – Sri Lanka"/><published>2022-11-11T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-11T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Most people got huge water bills after some time due to COVID-19. I wanted to double-check the calculation because the amount was somewhat big. Unlucky I didn’t find any online calculator that gets the job done (there was one in the waterboard, but it has a maximum limit of 60 days). So I went with the default option, Excel. I thought of sharing the excel workbook I used as It might be helpful to others. I really don’t know how the VAT calculation is done, so I used 15%. (Thanks to Madura for the suggested edit)</p> <p>Download the <a href="https://www.malinga.me/assets/pdf/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/Water-Bill-Calculator-8.xlsx">Water Bill Calculator</a></p> <p>These are the supporting document I used.</p> <p>Download <a href="https://www.malinga.me/assets/pdf/water-bill-calculator-sri-lanka/Water-Tariff-2294-51_English.pdf">Gazette for water tariff</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="other"/><category term="life"/><category term="other"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Updated 2022 Nov - Water Bill Calculator – Sri Lanka]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SLGS Scholarship Program 2021</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/slgs-scholarship-program-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SLGS Scholarship Program 2021"/><published>2021-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/slgs-scholarship-program-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/slgs-scholarship-program-2021/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/SLGS-Scholarship-Program-Malinga-Perera-724x1024-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/SLGS-Scholarship-Program-Malinga-Perera-724x1024-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/SLGS-Scholarship-Program-Malinga-Perera-724x1024-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/SLGS-Scholarship-Program-Malinga-Perera-724x1024.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society (SLGS) is a postgraduate society affiliated with the Graduate Student Association (GSA) at the University of Melbourne, Australia. We aim to advocate for the welfare of Sri Lankan graduate students and promote our culture and heritage among the multicultural community of the University, whilst also being committed to supporting undergraduate students in Sri Lanka. As part of our ongoing initiatives, we have strived to continue an annual scholarship program through which we award Sri Lankan undergraduate students a monthly scholarship for a period of one year. The main objective of this program is to financially assist and encourage students to achieve their academic goals.</p> <p>Over the years we have been able to raise sponsorships for more than 10 students which we can assure were of great support to the recipients. You can read the testimonials of the recent scholarship recipients in the flyer attached below and on our <a href="https://www.slgs.com.au/academic-scholarships-by-the-slgs/">website</a>. The recipients of the scholarships are selected based on their financial needs as well as their outstanding academic performance at the university. In 2021, the SLGS provided two scholarships worth LKR 120,000/-. Considering the multitude of applications we receive each year, we hope we can expand the number of scholarships provided under this program with your support. </p> <p>We are kindly inviting you to join hands with the SLGS on this great cause to brighten the future of talented young individuals in Sri Lanka. We hope this program would offer you the great joy and satisfaction of being able to give back to our motherland. You can support us by selecting one of the following support packages.</p> <ul> <li>Support a student for a year <strong>AUD 400</strong></li> <li>Support a student for 6 months <strong>AUD 200</strong></li> <li>Support a student for 3 months <strong>AUD 100</strong></li> <li>Support a student for a month <strong>AUD 35</strong></li> </ul> <p>Your kind donations can be made to either of the SLGS bank accounts given below. Please send us an email with your receipt to <a href="mailto:slgsunimelb@gmail.com">slgsunimelb@gmail.com</a>. </p> <p><strong>In Australia:</strong><br/> Account Name: <strong>Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society</strong><br/> Account No: <strong>1092 0366</strong><br/> BSB: <strong>063 238</strong><br/> Reference: <strong>SLGS Scholarship</strong></p> <p>Please feel free to contact us for further information regarding the scholarships or other funding opportunities.</p> <p>Email:  <a href="mailto:slgsunimelb@gmail.com">slgsunimelb@gmail.com</a></p> <p>Contact:  Co-Presidents Chinthani / Malinga</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="life"/><category term="slgs"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SLGS Scholarship Program 2021]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SQL Server Snapshot Creation Error - “All files must be specified for database snapshot creation”</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/sql-server-snapshot-creation-error-all-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SQL Server Snapshot Creation Error - “All files must be specified for database snapshot creation”"/><published>2021-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/sql-server-snapshot-creation-error-all-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/sql-server-snapshot-creation-error-all-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation.-1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation.-1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation.-1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation.-1.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>There are several reasons where you will get this error, but I’m going to talk about the one I faced and can be fixed in seconds. I was working with an IMDB dataset. The reason for my error was a database rename. I created the database initially with the name “IMDB” and later renamed it to “IMDB_001”.</p> <p>Command:</p> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CREATE DATABASE IMDB_001_snapshot ON ( NAME = IMDB_001, FILENAME ='--path--\IMDB_001_snapshot.ss' ) AS SNAPSHOT OF IMDB_001;</code></p> <p>Error: All files must be specified for database snapshot creation. Missing the file “IMDB”. (5127) (SQLExecDirectW)’)</p> <p>Fix (Using SSMS):</p> <p>Right-click on the database &gt; Properties &gt; (left menu)Files &gt; Rename the file logical names to current database name (in my case to IMDB_001)</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/All-files-must-be-specified-for-database-snapshot-creation.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="database"/><category term="microsoft"/><category term="sql-server"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SQL Server Snapshot Creation Error - "All files must be specified for database snapshot creation"]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Codenames Duet Editable Digital Mission Map</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/codenames-duet-editable-digital-map/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codenames Duet Editable Digital Mission Map"/><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/codenames-duet-editable-digital-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/codenames-duet-editable-digital-map/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me-1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me-1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me-1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me-1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p><em><strong>Codenames Duet</strong></em> keeps the basic elements of <em>Codenames</em> — give one-word clues to try to get someone to identify your agents among those on the table — but now you’re working together as a team to find all of your agents. (Why you don’t already know who your agents are is a question that Congressional investigators will get on your back about later!) - <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/224037/codenames-duet">BoardGamesGeek</a></p> <p>I found it easy to have a digital map when you are playing an online version (ex: https://codenames.game/). This map can keep your status (editable).</p> <p><strong>How to use:</strong> Each mission has two parameters. The first number is the total number of turns. When setting up a mission, put this many tokens in the time bank and leave the rest in the box. Moscow uses only 8, while Berlin uses all 11. Cairo uses 9, just like the standard Prague mission. The second number is the number of acceptable mistakes. Only this many tokens are bystander side up. - <em>Rule Book</em></p> <p><a href="https://www.malinga.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me.pdf"><strong>Download the Codenames Duet Editable Digital Mission Map</strong></a><a href="https://www.malinga.me/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Codenames-duet-digital-map-malinga-me.pdf"> Download</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="boardgames"/><category term="codenames"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Codenames Duet Editable Digital Mission Map]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sri Lankan New Year 2021, Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society (SLGS)</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/sri-lankan-new-year-2021-slgs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sri Lankan New Year 2021, Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society (SLGS)"/><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/sri-lankan-new-year-2021-slgs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/sri-lankan-new-year-2021-slgs/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society (SLGS) of the University of Melbourne organized “අවුරුදු උදානය 2021” to celebrate the Sri Lankan New Year 2021. Below are some clicks from my camera.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/DSC_0134-scaled-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/DSC_0134-scaled-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/DSC_0134-scaled-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/DSC_0134-scaled.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="life"/><category term="life"/><category term="slgs"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sri Lankan New Year 2021, Sri Lankan Graduates’ Society (SLGS)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">VS Code Won’t Open After Unplanned Restart (Failed to deserialize the V8 snapshot blob)</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/vs-code-wont-open-after-unplanned-restart-failed-to-deserialize-the-v8-snapshot-blob/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VS Code Won’t Open After Unplanned Restart (Failed to deserialize the V8 snapshot blob)"/><published>2021-02-11T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-11T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/vs-code-wont-open-after-unplanned-restart-failed-to-deserialize-the-v8-snapshot-blob</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/vs-code-wont-open-after-unplanned-restart-failed-to-deserialize-the-v8-snapshot-blob/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/vs_code_wont_open/vs_code_wont_open-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/vs_code_wont_open/vs_code_wont_open-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/vs_code_wont_open/vs_code_wont_open-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/vs_code_wont_open/vs_code_wont_open.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The visual studio was running fine in my machine till an unplanned restart happened. Soon after restart VS didn’t open giving me the below error. I reinstalled the Visual Studio Code without uninstalling which fixed the issue. In addition, it started without any loss to previous plugins and open projects. Error</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Fatal error in , line 0
Failed to deserialize the V8 snapshot blob. This can mean that the snapshot blob file is corrupted or missing.
FailureMessage Object: 00000071D3DFF2C0
1: 00007FF60A57E91F node::Buffer::New+130911
2: 00007FF60A3F7CDA IsSandboxedProcess+1850986
3: 00007FF608E1D798 v8::Isolate::Initialize+744
4: 00007FF60A3FD1A0 uv_mutex_unlock+21184
5: 00007FF607A28793 std::__1::__vector_base &gt;::__end_cap+102515
6: 00007FF607AE56C8 v8::internal::JSMemberBase::JSMemberBase+54872
7: 00007FF6079513A0 Ordinal0+5024
8: 00007FF60D6FDB02 uv_random+18066594
9: 00007FFB77EF4034 BaseThreadInitThunk+20
10: 00007FFB781F3691 RtlUserThreadStart+33
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="programming"/><category term="coding"/><category term="programming"/><category term="tools"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Won’t Open After Unplanned Restart (Failed to deserialize the V8 snapshot blob)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Scrum] Adding new priorities to the current sprint</title><link href="https://www.malinga.me/scrum-adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Scrum] Adding new priorities to the current sprint"/><published>2021-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.malinga.me/scrum-adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.malinga.me/scrum-adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/images/Scrum-Adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/images/Scrum-Adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/images/Scrum-Adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/images/Scrum-Adding-new-priorities-to-the-current-sprint1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 mx-auto d-block" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>We see changes in priorities from time to time. With the nature of the team, we need to expect newer priorities even in the middle of a sprint. New priorities can come as a production issue or a new feature development with higher ROI. I work in a service team where we get high priority items all the time. I like to talk about how we handle those issues in this article.</p> <h2 id="what-is-the-ideal-way-to-handle-additional-requirements-real-scrum-way">What is the ideal way to handle Additional Requirements [real scrum way]</h2> <blockquote> <p>Once a sprint begins, you cannot add requirements or stories to the backlog</p> </blockquote> <p>It is simple as above; We cannot add additional requirements to the sprint after it begins. In an ideal world, if we do not obey at least one Scrum rule, we cannot claim that we are following Scrum. Therefore, if we need to align to pure Scrum, we need to close the current sprint, prioritize the backlog, and start a new sprint with a new priority list.</p> <h2 id="ideal-way-doesnt-seems-to-be-efficient-for-us">Ideal way doesn’t seems to be efficient for us</h2> <p>As we already know, there are so many hybrid versions of scrum due to scrum being inefficient in some situations. In our case, all members get some ad-hoc tasks while some team members get many ad-hoc tasks (related database administration). Therefore, we decided to fork out the original scrum and make an efficient version of it.</p> <p>We tried so many things, and I like to share some of the things we tried and how they worked out for us. Please remember that not all of us were fully cross-functional because we were new to pure scrum.</p> <h4 id="solution-1-identify-a-member-that-can-attend-most-of-those-ad-hoc-tasks-and-keep-him-out-of-the-sprint">Solution 1: Identify a member that can attend most of those ad-hoc tasks and keep him out of the sprint</h4> <p>IInitially, this seemed to work well, and there was less effect on the current sprint from the ad-hoc tasks. However, with time, we identify that even though there is a separate person for ad-hoc tasks, he needed help from the others. At the same time, we saw that he was idle on some occasions where there was enough work in the sprint backlog. Moreover, as he was out of the sprint, it was hard to keep track of him. With all those drawbacks, we decided to get him back into the sprint and search for other options.</p> <h4 id="solution-2-estimating-the-ad-hoc-work-in-the-panning-and-have-a-story-for-it">Solution 2: Estimating the ad-hoc work in the panning and have a story for it</h4> <p>Our next move was to calculate the time the person mentioned above spent on the ad-hoc tasks and estimate it in the planning meeting. Here we created an ad-hoc story for several members and tried to estimate them with our knowledge from the past sprints. We hoped that we would better estimate future sprints with experience. Unfortunately, we identified that this ad-hoc task estimate was wrong and changed drastically from sprint to sprint.</p> <h4 id="solution-3-limiting-the-sprint-length-to-one-week">Solution 3: Limiting the sprint length to one week</h4> <p>Limiting the sprint length to one week was one of the best decisions we ever made. We could hold most of the ad-hoc tasks to the next sprint with this change. Most people agreed to wait for 3-4 days to get the task done. Still, some tickets required immediate attention (e.g. high critical production issues). With this change, we observed that deviation in the estimates in the ad-hoc task ticket was reduced. After this, following the Scrum practices were very much simplified.</p> <h4 id="solution-4-removing-the-ad-hoc-story-from-the-sprint">Solution 4: Removing the ad-hoc story from the sprint</h4> <p>We saw that the ad-hoc task had some advert effect on the burn-down and velocity charts. Some sprints did not have a lot of ad-hoc tasks, but the total estimate was counted in the velocity. In addition, these stories did not have clear and well-defined DoDs (Definition of Done ). Therefore, we decided to keep the ad-hoc story out of the sprint and let the velocity fall to some extent. Here some members worked on the ad-hoc tasks and tracked the ad-hoc story. However, this story was not be counted in the team velocity as it was out of the sprint.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>With many changes and experiments, we decided to keep some changes and decided to revert some. Finally, we went with 1-week sprints and had an ad-hoc story to track the ad-hoc tasks outside the sprint. Other than that, we took several actions to ensure we had minimum ad-hoc tasks.</p> <ol> <li>Building good communication channels with other teams and getting to know about the upcoming changes before the planning meeting</li> <li>Notifying all other teams that we are following Scrum and not accepting any tickets after the planning meeting. (Not entirely true)</li> </ol> <p>We cannot call this SCRUM anymore. However, this version of SCRUM seems to work for us, and it helped us follow other scrum-related ceremonies and traditions perfectly. We came close to Scrum by going a little away from pure Scrum.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="software-engineering"/><category term="scrum"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[[Scrum] Adding new priorities to the current sprint]]></summary></entry></feed>